- This video is about learning styles.
这期视频我们聊聊「学习风格」
What kind of learner are you?
你是哪种学习者？
- Oh yeah, I'm a visual person so I have to see things, yeah.
呃  我是视觉型的那种  所以我得看着东西来学
- Oh yeah, same.
- 我也一样
- I think visual learner.
- 视觉型的
- Visual.
- 视觉那种
- I mean, like, I remember formulas like auditory.
- 我用听的方式来记公式
- I need to be like, interacting with the material.
- 我要用交互式的方式去学
- I like to learn by doing it myself.
- 我喜欢通过自己动手来学
- Very hands-on.
- 上手去做
- Hands-on learner.
- 动手的那种类型
- Hands-on?
- 要上手的
- So like, if I have a model, I'd like to look at that and look it over.
- 比如我拿着个模型，我倾向于仔细地把它里外看个遍
- Part of this video was sponsored by Google Search.
- 本视频部分内容由不存在的搜索引擎赞助
There is this idea in education that
教育领域普遍认为
everyone has their own preferred way of learning,
每个人都有自己所倾向的学习方式
their so-called learning style.
也就是通常所说的学习风格
If information is presented in accordance with the learning style,
如果呈现信息的方式和学生的学习风格相匹配
well, then they'll learn better.
他们将能够学得更好
Now, there are dozens of different learning style theories,
现如今  人们提出了几十种有关教育风格的理论
but the most common one identifies four main learning styles,
其中最广为认知的理论指出  有四种主要的学习方式
visual, auditory, reading-writing, and kinesthetic or VARK for short.
视觉、听觉、读写以及动手，简称 VARK
Visual learners learn best from images, demonstrations, and pictures.
视觉学习者从图像、图示等中学习效果最好
- People may say things, but I can't really take it in.
靠别人的言语来让我理解事物  效果并不好
I just gotta see 'em act it out or write it or something.
我需要通过一些动作或者写出来这样来理解
- Auditory learners learn best from listening to an explanation.
听觉学习者听别人讲解学习效果最佳
- Like in school, I was always engaged in the lecture
- 在学校的时候我在课上很积极
and that was usually good enough to pass a test.
也很有利于帮助我考试通过
- Reading-writing learners learn best from reading and writing.
- 读写学习者通过读和写来达到最佳的学习效果
- Like I can get pretty much anything out of reading a textbook or something.
- 我读课本的时候能读出挺多东西的
- And kinesthetic learners learn best by doing,
- 动手的学习者最有效的学习方式
physically interacting with the world.
是真正的去接触东西，去实践
- Hands-on.
- 上手去做
You have to touch things, you have to play with things,
你需要去接触和把玩那些东西
you know, it's a contact sport. You have to do it yourself.
这个东西是要接触的 你必须得亲自去做才能学到 [REVIEW: "it"?]
- I want to try something with you, a little experiment.
- 我想和你来做个小实验
I want to show you 10 pictures of things
- 我现在给你看十个东西的图
and I don't want you to say anything while you're looking at them,
你看的时候不要说话
and at the end of the 10 you tell me how many you can remember.
看完了以后把记得的告诉我
- Okay.
好
- Okay?
- Okay.
- 可以吗
- 可
- Okay.
- 嗯
- Now, learning styles make intuitive sense because we know everyone is different.
每个人都是独特的 这让我们感觉 大家自然而然会有不同的学习风格
Some people have better spacial reasoning.
有些人空间感知能力强
Others have better listening comprehension.
有些人听力理解能力强
We know some people are better readers
有些人读文章强
while others are good with their hands.
有些人动手能力强
- It's sort of very much fits with a broad strain
这和一直流传下来的
of thought in the recent Western tradition is,
近代的西方思想非常吻合
we're all unique, we're all different.
我们每个人都是独特、不同的
And so you don't want to say, like, everybody learns the same way.
所以没必要每个人都用同一种方式来学习
That sort of conflicts with our feelings about what it means to be human.
学习方式完全一致与人类的意义相冲突
- So doesn't it make sense that
那这样说的话
people should learn better in their own preferred learning style?
人们以自己的学习方式学习效果更好？
Well, teachers certainly seem to think so.
啊，老师们当然这么想
A survey of nearly 400 teachers from the UK and
英国和荷兰 400 名左右的教师里
the Netherlands found that over 90% believed that
有超过 90% 的认为
individuals learn better when they receive information in their preferred learning style.
学生以他们的学习风格接收信息学得更快
- Just like every professor has a different style of teaching,
- 教授有不同的教学方式
you have a different style of learning.
学生也有不同的学习方式
- But when his teacher starts using visuals,
- 当老师开始使用视觉方式教学时
Johnathan finds it easier to focus and understand the material
Johnathan 发现他理解课堂内容更快了 听课更专注了
so he might be a visual learner.
因此他可能是个视觉学习者
- Can you tell me what that means to you?
你能说一下作为一个视觉学习者
Like, what does it mean to be a visual learner?
这对你来说有什么样的意义吗
- To me it means that... for me, to learn something,
- 对我来说 这意味着我学东西的时候
sometimes you need to draw it or I need to write it down
有时得要画出来或者写下来
or I need to see a picture or a movie.
或者看图像、影片
- For example, science classes, I get bored easily just listening
例如科学课上听着听着我就睡着了
and I think it's more interesting for me to actually be able to do it.
我觉得  要是能让我上手做的话  我会更喜欢这个课
- How do you know that you're a visual learner?
- 你咋知道你是视觉学习者的
- I don't, I just assumed.
- 我没法证明  我只是猜的
- To take advantage of learning styles then teachers need to do two things.
- 要把学生学习风格的优势运用起来 老师要做两件事
First, identify the learning style of each of their students.
首先他们要弄清楚他们各个学生的学习风格
And second, teach each student in accordance with their learning style.
然后根据各个学生的学习风格来教学
On the VARK website it says,
在 VARK 的网站上
once you know about VARK, its power to explain things will be a revelation.
它说你一旦知道了这东西 你便知道了如何教别人的惊天秘密
But before you take an online learning styles quiz,
但是在你跑去测你的学习风格之前
it's a good idea to ask, do learning styles even exist?
想想看 学习风格真的存在吗？
I mean, do you have one?
你有学习风格吗？
And if you're taught in accordance with it, would you learn better?
如果有人按着你的学习风格教你 你会学得更好吗
Well, you could test this by running a randomized control trial
这个东西可以通过一个控制变量的随机试验来检验
where first you would identify learners
首先你先找到一批的不同学习风格的学习者
with at least two different learning styles, say visual and auditory
假设他们的学习风格有视觉和听觉的
and then randomly assign learners to one of two educational presentations,
然后把他们随机分到两个课堂里
one visual, one auditory.
一个视觉教学，一个听觉教学
So for half of the students, the experience will match their learning style
那这样一半的学生会以他们的学习方式学习
and for the other half it won't.
另外一半则不会
And then you give everyone the same test.
在此之后给他们一份测试题
If the learning style hypothesis is correct,
如果学习风格的假说是对的
the results should show better performance when the presentation
在匹配自身学习风格的课堂里  上课的学生
matches the learning style than when they're mismatched.
应该考得比那些风格不匹配的学生要好
I tried a very unscientific version of this experiment on the street.
我在大街上很不严谨地进行了一下这个实验
For some people, I matched their learning style
对于一部分人，我展示这些东西的方式和他们的学习风格一致
so I showed visual learners pictures of 10 items,
例如我给（一部分）视觉学习者看了十个事物的图像
but for other visual learners I read out the items instead.
但是对于另一部分的视觉学习者 我则是把这些东西读出来
Bell, penguin, sun.
铃铛、企鹅、太阳
- Okay, I'm maxed out.
- 好了我就记得这么多了~~别念了~~
- How many can you remember?
- 你记住了多少？
- I don't know.
- 不懂了
- Hair, knife, duck, heart, butterfly.
- 头发、刀、鸭、心、蝴蝶
- Apple, bicycle, guitar.
- 苹果、单车、吉他
- There was a spider.
- 蜘蛛
Did I say eye already?
眼睛说过了吗
- Trumpet, pear.
- Pear.
- 小号，梨
- 梨
- Butterfly.
- Duck.
- 蝴蝶
- 鸭鸭
- Knife.
- Boat.
- 刀
- 船
- Heart.
- Knife.
- 心
- 刀
- Heart.
- 心
- I couldn't tell you the rest, that's all I got.
- 我就记得这么多了
- Most people could remember
- 许多人都只记住了
only about five or six things.
五到六件事物
- Yeah, yeah.
- Six, six is not bad.
六个 不错
- All right.
- 好吧
- Six.
- Six out of 10
- 六个
- 十个里面记住了六个
which is not bad, right?
- Oh, all right, yeah.
不错
- 好
- That's a passing score.
- 及格了
Candle.
- Oh.
蜡烛
- 啊...
- Candle.
- Everyone forgets the candle.
- 蜡烛
- 没人记得蜡烛
But a few could remember substantially more,
不过有几个人记得还挺多的
say, eight or nine items.
记了七八个
- Bug, I don't know if I said bug.
- 我说过虫虫了吗
Guitar, bike, eye, bell, spoon, sun, chair.
吉他，单车，眼睛，铃铛，勺子，太阳，椅子
I'm forgetting the last two.
最后两个不记得了
- That's pretty good.
- Eight is really good.
- 很棒了
- 八个真的挺不错了
- Oh, cool.
- 好诶
- Nine?
- Nine out of 10.
- 九个
- 十个里记住了九个
- Nine, very impressive.
- 九个，真的好强
But the reason didn't seem to be
但是看上去原因并不在于
because the presentation matched their preferred learning style
告诉他们的方式和他们的学习风格一致
but because they employed a memory strategy.
而是因为他们用了记忆的技巧
- So as you were showing I was making an order in my head.
- 你在给我看的时候我脑内就形成了一个顺序
So as I saw more I would just add it to the list
新加进来一个我就把它加到列表里
and I was repeating the list as I was looking at them
我回答的时候就会像把这个列表念出来一样
so I could just say it out loud.
所以就挺轻松的
- Did you try a strategy while you were looking at those pictures?
- 你记忆的时候用了什么特殊技巧吗
- Yeah, yeah.
- 是
So I guess I tried creating a story
我把它们连成了一个故事
'cause it's easier to remember a story than just individual objects.
这样记起来比这些零散的要轻松
So I tried to tie it all into one story.
所以我刚刚尝试把它串成故事
- This is all obviously anecdotal evidence,
当然这不是太正经的依据了
but rigorous studies like the one I outlined have been conducted.
但是实际上类似的研究已经做过了
For example, one looked at visualizers versus verbalizers
他研究的不是视觉或者听觉学习者
instead of visual versus auditory learners.
而是图形学习者和文字学习者
The study was computer-based,
这是一个基于计算机的测试
so first students' learning styles were assessed using questions like,
首先这些学生会回答一些问题
would you rather read a paragraph or see a diagram describing an atom?
例如你喜欢看原子的文字还是示意图的描述
The researchers also provided some challenging explanations
研究者还整了一些复杂的介绍
with two buttons, visual help or verbal help.
配上“图形解说”和“文字解说”的两个按钮
The visual one played a short animation
图形解说会放一个小动画
whereas the verbal help gave a written explanation.
文字解说则会弹出一段文字
From these measures combined,
通过这些方式
the researchers categorized the students as either visualizers or verbalizers
研究者将这些学生分成了视觉和文字学习者两类
and then the students were randomly assigned
然后将他们随机分配到一个电子电路课堂
to go through a text-based or picture-based lesson on electronics.
这个课堂有文字和图像两种授课方式
When a student hovered their mouse over key words
当学生把指针悬停在关键词上时
in the lesson in the text-based group, a definition and clarification came up.
文字授课方式的课堂将显示它的定义和解释
But in the picture group,
而图像授课方式的课堂
an annotated diagram was shown instead.
则是显示一个示意图
And after the lesson, the students did a test to assess their learning.
上完课后，测试者发给学生一套测试题来检验学习情况
The students whose preferred learning style matched their instruction
测试结果表明学习的方式与学习风格一致的学生
performed no better on the tests than those whose instruction was mismatched.
并没有比不一致的好
The researchers ran the test again with 61 non-college-educated adults
测试者还在 61 个没受过大学教育的学生上做了同样的测试
and found exactly the same result.
结果是一致的
But learning styles are a preference
但是  学习风格是种「偏好」
so how strongly do learners stick to their preference?
那么  学生们的偏好固定吗
Well, in a 2018 study during the first week of semester,
在 2018 年的一项研究中  在学期伊始
over 400 students at a university in Indiana completed the VARK questionnaire
印第安纳州一所大学的400多名学生  填写了VARK调查问卷
and they were classified according to their learning style.
他们根据问卷得出的学习方法  被分为了四大组
Then at the end of the semester
到了学期结束时
the same students completed a study strategy questionnaire.
这帮学生又填写了实际学习策略的调查问卷
So how did they actually study during the term?
他们在这个学期实际上是怎么学的
Well, an overwhelming majority of students used study strategies
占压倒性多数的学生
which were supposedly incompatible with their learning style,
使用的学习策略反而并不符合自身的学习风格
and the minority of students who did
而极少数使用了相符策略的学生
did not perform significantly differently on the assessments in the course.
在课程的考试中并没有与前者产生显著差异
The visual auditory reading-writing, kinesthetic or VARK model
视觉、听觉、读写、动手模型（即 VARK 模型）
came about from Neil Fleming, a school inspector in New Zealand.
由新西兰的一位学校督学——尼尔・佛莱明提出
Describing the origins of VARK he says,
他是这样描述他如何发明 VARK 的
I was puzzled when I observed excellent teachers who did not reach some learners
让我很困惑的是  我观察到最厉害的老师也有教不会的学生
and poor teachers who did.
但最差的老师反而能教会这些学生
I decided to try to solve this puzzle.
我想试试去解决这一问题
There are, of course, many reasons for what I observed.
当然  我观察到了不少缘由
But one topic that seemed to hold some magic, some explanatory power,
但我觉得有一个原因是最有说服力的
was preferred modes of learning, modal preferences.
那就是「偏好的学习模式」或称「典型偏好」
And thus, VARK was born.
VARK 因此而生
There was no study that revealed students naturally cluster into four distinct groups.
原来  研究并没有证明学生会天然的分成四个组别
Just some magic that might explain
why some teachers can reach students while others can't.
But how can this be?
If we accept that some people are more skilled
如果我们认可这种观点  有些人相对更擅长处理、记忆某几类因素  比如图像或声音
at interpreting and remembering certain kinds of stimuli
than others like visual or auditory,
then why don't we see differences in learning or recall with different presentations?
为何在学习或者回忆事物的测试中  显示不出差别呢
Well, it's because what we actually want people to recall
这是因为  其实人们需要记忆的东西
is not the precise nature of the images or the pitch or quality of the sound.
并不是图像的精确性质  亦非声音的音调和质量
It's the meaning behind the presentations.
要记的是各种表现形式背后的「实际含义」
There are some tasks that obviously require the use of a particular modality.
有些任务必然需要使用某一类特定的表现形式
Learning about music, for example, should have an auditory component.
比如说  学音乐肯定依赖于声音
Similarly, learning about geography will involve looking at maps.
类似的  学地理肯定需要看地图
And some people will have greater aptitude to learn one task over another.
有些人天生就比别人更擅长学习某类任务
Someone with perfect pitch, for example,
比如说  有绝对音感的人肯定更容易记住音乐中的音调
will be better able to recall certain tones in music.
Someone with excellent visual-spatial reasoning
视觉-空间推理能力强的人  能更准确地在国家地图上定位
will be better at learning the locations of countries on a map.
But the claim of learning style theories is that
但学习风格理论宣称  这些偏好性不管学啥东西都是不变的
these preferences will be consistent across learning domains.
The person with perfect pitch should learn everything better auditorily
有绝对音感的人  碰到一切关乎声音的内容时  都应该学得更快
but that is clearly not the case.
这很明显不合道理
Most people will learn geography better with a map.
大部分人学好地理靠的是地图
Review articles of learning styles consistently conclude
专家审查了学习风格的文章后  一致得出
there is no credible evidence that learning styles exist.
尚没有显著的证据能证明学习风格真的存在
In a 2009 review, the researchers note,
在 2009 年的审核中  研究者指出
the contrast between the enormous popularity
学习风格论在教育界的流行  跟它缺乏可信证据的事实  形成了鲜明对比
of the learning styles approach within education
and the lack of credible evidence for its utility is,
学习风格论在教育界的流行  跟它缺乏可信证据的事实  形成了鲜明对比
in our opinion, striking and disturbing.
我们认为这很离谱  这样的现状让我们很不安
If classification of students' learning styles has practical utility,
要是对学生的学习风格进行分类有实际作用的话
it remains to be demonstrated.
我们还愿意去论证一下学习风格论
- What we're expecting is, if your style was honored
我们本来期望的是  在遵循了相符的学习风格的情况下
you're going to perform better than if
你应该比使用了相异学习风格的表现要更好
you had some experience that conflicted with your style.
And this is where we don't see any support for the learning styles theory.
我们在这一点上看不到任何支持学习风格论的证据
- One of the reasons many people find learning styles
人们对学习风格论如此的深信不疑
so convincing is because they already believe it to be true.
或许是因为他们先相信学习风格是真实存在的
For example, they might already think that they're a visual learner,
他们可能已经相信自己是视觉学习者
and then when a teacher shows them a diagram of, say, a bike pump
如果老师给他们展示了一份图解  比如说自行车打气筒
and suddenly the concept clicks,
然后学生一下子开窍了
well, they interpret this as evidence for their visual learning style.
他们就认为  这恰好能作为证据  印证自己是个视觉学习着
- You already believe that learning styles is right.
你先入为主的认为学习方法是正确的
When you have an experience the first thing you think is,
当你从实践中获得经验时  你第一时间先想
is that in some way consistent with learning styles?
它符不符合我的学习风格
And if it is, you don't think further.
如果符合  你就不再深入思考了
- When in reality that diagram
那个图解说不定只是一个对任何学习者都有帮助的优质图解
might just be a great diagram that would have helped anyone learn.
When we already believe the world to be a certain way,
你头脑中已经给世界画了个框框（认为世界就是这样运行的）
then we interpret new experiences to fit with those beliefs
然后对一切新的经验  不管三七二十一就往框框里套
whether they actually do or not.
So if learning styles don't improve learning, then what does?
那么，如果学习风格对学习并无帮助，那什么才有帮助呢
Well, there's a large body of literature that supports the claim that
事实上  有大量文献支持的一个观点是
everyone learns better with multimodal approaches
使用多种感官形式来学习的效果会优于单一形式
where words and pictures are presented together
同时展示文本和图像的效果要优于只展现其中一者
rather than either words or pictures alone.
Now there's gonna be words as well as the picture.
接下来  文字是和图像一起展示的
We're gonna see if this is any better.
看看结果会不会更好一点
This is known as the multimedia effect,
这种效应被称为“多媒体效应”
and it explains in part, at least,
它至少在一定程度上解释了
why videos can be such powerful tools for learning
拥有图像和旁白的视频  为什么能成为一种强大的学习工具
when the narration complements the visuals.
Duck.
- Duck.
鸭子
- Heart.
心
- In my PhD research, I found explicit discussion of misconceptions was essential
在我的博士研究中我发现  在物理学入门的多媒体教学中
in multimedia teaching for introductory physics.
对错误概念的明确讨论是至关重要的
- How many is that?
- Six.
总共多少
六个
- Six, okay, that's good.
六个，不错嘛
- That is a whole 50% better.
这好了一半呢
Do you think that was easier?
你觉得这样更简单吗
- Yeah, yeah, 100%, 100%.
- Yeah, with the words, yeah.
- 对，百分百更简单
- 对，有了文字更简单，对
- Ultimately, the most important thing for learning
学习中最终极、最重要的特质
is not the way the information is presented
不是呈现信息的方式
but what is happening inside the learner's head.
而是学习者脑袋里有何过程
People learn best when they're actively thinking about the material,
人们学得最牢固的时候  是他们活跃地思考材料、
solving problems or imagining what happens if different variables change.
解决问题、或是想象不同变量的变化方式
I talked about how and why we learn best
我之前聊过学习的最佳方式、为什么这方式最佳
in my video, "The Science of Thinking" so check that out.
快去康康我之前的视频「思考的科学」
Now, the truth is, there are many evidence-based teaching methods that improve learning.
真相是  有许多教学方法已得到证据佐证  有助于学习
Learning styles is just not one of them.
但学习风格论不能算在里面
And it is likely, given the prevalence of the learning styles misconception
鉴于对学习风格广泛存在的误解
that it actually makes learning worse.
它很可能实际上会让学习效果更差
I mean, learning styles give teachers unnecessary things to worry about,
我的意思是  学习风格论给教师带来了不必要的担心
and they make some students reluctant to engage with certain types of instruction.
还导致一些学生不愿参与某些类别的教学
And all the time and money spent on learning styles and related training
在学习风格一脉的培训上浪费的时间和金钱
could be better spent on interventions that actually improve learning.
本可以更好地用于真正改善学习的措施上
You are not a visual learner nor an auditory learner nor a kinesthetic learner,
你并不是什么视觉、听觉、动手学习者
or more accurately, you are all these kinds of learner in one.
更准确地说  你是依赖于所有感官的学习者  是上面的集合体
The best learning experiences are those
最好的学习实践  应囊括了对同一事物的多种理解角度
that involve multiple different ways of understanding the same thing.
And best of all, this strategy works not just for one subset of people but for everyone.
并且最好的是  这样的策略不是对一部分人  而是对所有人都适用